A Guide to the Correspondence Files of Special Collections, University of Virginia Library 1931-1990s
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Correspondence Files of Special Collections, University of Virginia Library 1931-1990s
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-12/11/4.021
This collection is comprised of ca. 300,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Stored off-site. Users must request boxes 48 hours in advance of desired use. Neither drop-in nor next-day requests can be fulfilled. For additional information, contact Special Collections.
Access restrictions apply to specific student and staff records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.). Other records may also be restricted.
Acquisition Information
The files were an internal archival transfer on April 10, 2002.
Scope and Content
The Special Collections Correspondence files pconsist chiefly of the general correspondence files of Special Collections of the University of Virginia Library and like files of its predecessors, the Rare Book Department and the Manuscripts Department.
Included are patron use ledgers; patron request slips; Manuscripts Field Agent files; student assistant and employee files; dealer correspondence; thank you letters; and reference letters.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in four series: Series I: Correspondence (General); Series II: Patron-Use Files [1991- ]; Series III: Manuscripts Field Agent's Files; Series IV: Special Collections Student Assistants and Employee Files [ -1995]
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence (General)
  - Manuscripts Department Correspondence [ante 1990] and Patron-Use Files (Box A28-7A through A29-17T)
    - Adams papers 1967 (Box A28-7A)
    - Akerman, Amos Tappan (Box A28-7A)
    - Alarm System 1980-1990 (Box A28-7A)
    - Albemarle County records (Box A28-7A)
    - American Rhododendron Society (Box A28-7A)
    - Anderson, Ellen Graham (Box A28-7A)
    - Annual Reports - University Archives 1976-1986 (Box A28-7A)
    - Annual Reports - Technical Services Section 1973-1984 (Box A28-7A)
    - A Misc. - Field Archivist's Papers (Box A29-12J)
    - A Misc. (Box A29-12J)
    - Anderson, William A. (Box A29-12J)
    - American Literary Manuscripts (Box A29-12J)
    - Adair, Douglass (see also World Turned Upside Down) (Box A29-12K)
    - Adams Family - Lists of holdings (Box A29-12K)
    - Adams Family (Box A29-12K)
    - Adams, John Quincy (Box A29-12K)
    - Adams, Tom (Box A29-12K)
    - Affleck, Charles J. (Box A29-12K)
    - Albemarle Pippen (Box A29-12K)
    - Albemarle County - Black Citizens (Box A29-12K)
    - Alden, John 1952-1955 (Box A29-12K)
    - Alderman, Edwin (Box A29-12K)
    - Alexandria Imprints (Box A29-12K)
    - American Council of Learned Societies (Box A29-12K)
    - American Imprints - Inventory (see also Sondley Library) (Box A29-12K)
    - Amherst County Virginia (Box A29-12K)
    - Ammon, Harry (Box A29-12K)
    - Andrews, Matthew Page (Box A29-12K)
    - Anthony, Emma G. (Box A29-12K)
    - Applacian Trail Club (Box A29-12K)
    - Annual Reports - MSS dept. 1958-1987 (Box A28-7B)
    - Annual Reports - Public Services section 1970-1986 (Box A28-7B)
    - Annual Reports - Asst. Curator 1975-1985 (Box A28-7B)
    - Annual Reports - MSS Cataloguer 1970-1985 (Box A28-7B)
    - Annual Reports - Field Archivist (Box A28-7B)
    - Appraisals - General (Box A28-7B)
    - Appraisals 1965-1969 (Box A28-7B)
    - Appraisals 1970-1980 (Box A28-7C)
    - Appraisals 1981-1989 (Box A28-7D)
    - Appraisals - Policy Review 1988-1989 (Box A28-7D)
    - Architectural Records (Box A28-7E)
    - Araldi Manuscripts (Box A28-7E)
    - Archives - Alderman Library 50th anniv. (Box A28-7E)
    - Archives - Morea lawsuit (Box A28-7E)
    - Arnold, Matthew (Box A28-7E)
    - Art Commission (Box A28-7E)
    - Art Index - pavilions, etc. (Box A28-7E)
    - Art Objects inventory (Box A28-7E)
    - Arts Festival (Box A28-7E)
    - Arts Council of Great Britain (Box A28-7E)
    - Ashby, Gen. Turner (Box A28-7F)
    - Ash Lawn (Box A28-7F)
    - Associated Press - photos (Box A28-7F)
    - Associates of the University of Virginia Library 1978-1990 (Box A28-7F)
    - Associates of the University of Virginia Library - Board Minutes (1987- ) (Box A28-7F)
    - Associates of the University of Virginia Library - Financial Reports (1988- ) (Box A28-7F)
    - Association of Research Libraries - Survey on Special Collections (Box A28-7F)
    - Association of Southeastern Research Libraries (Box A28-7F)
    - Astor, Nancy (Box A28-7F)
    - Atkinson-Chamberlayne, Mrs. Anne (Box A28-7F)
    - Atkinson, Roger (Box A28-7F)
    - Auchincloss, Louis S. (Box A28-7G)
    - Auden, W. H. (see also James, Henry) (Box A28-7G)
    - Audubon (Box A28-7G)
    - Augusta County (Box A28-7G)
    - Aylett, William (Box A28-7G)
    - B misc. 1956-1970 (Box A28-7G)
    - B misc. 1931-1955 (Box A28-7H)
    - B misc. 1971-1987 (Box A28-7I)
    - B misc. 1988-1989 (Box A28-7J)
    - Babb, James T. (Box A28-7K)
    - Baber, Mrs. Charles G. (Box A28-7K)
    - Backwoods Press (Box A28-7K)
    - Bacon, Francis (see also Machiavels) (Box A28-7K)
    - Bacon's Rebellion (see also Firestone, Harry) (Box A28-7K)
    - Baer, Elizabeth (Box A28-7K)
    - Bagby, Ellen (Box A28-7K)
    - Bahn, Gilbert S. (Box A28-7K)
    - Balch Family papers (Box A28-7K)
    - Bailey, Whitman (Box A28-7K)
    - Baird, Mrs. Charles (Box A28-7K)
    - Bakeless, John (Box A28-7K)
    - Baker, Carlos / Peters Rushton Seminar (Box A28-7K)
    - Baker, James B. (Box A28-7K)
    - Bakken, Douglas A. (Box A28-7K)
    - Balch, Emily Clarck (Box A28-7K)
    - Ball, Mrs. James M., Jr. (Box A28-7K)
    - Balloch, W.W. (Box A28-7K)
    - Balmain, Alexander (Box A28-7K)
    - Balz, Albert George Adams (Box A28-7K)
    - Bane, Frank (Box A28-7L)
    - Banister, John (Box A28-7L)
    - Bankes mss (Box A28-7L)
    - Banta, R.E. (Box A28-7L)
    - Bantz Papers (Box A28-7L)
    - Baptist Associations (Box A28-7L)
    - Baptists (Box A28-7L)
    - Barbee, David Rankin (Box A28-7L)
    - Barbour Papers (Box A28-7L)
    - Barbour, Philip P. - papers (Box A28-7L)
    - Barclay, Julius (Box A28-7L)
    - Bardin, James Cook (Box A28-7L)
    - Barker, T.C. (Box A28-7L)
    - Barksdale, Edward & Garland (Box A28-7L)
    - Barlow, Joel (Box A28-7L)
    - Barr, Stringfellow (Box A28-7L)
    - Barracks (Box A28-7L)
    - Barrett, Clifton Waller - mss from Newberry Library (Box A28-7L)
    - Barrett, Clifton Waller (Box A28-7L)
    - Barrett, Clifton Waller - bills (Box A28-7L)
    - Barrett, Clifton Waller 1941-1956, 1978-1989 (Box A28-7M)
    - Barrett, Clifton Waller - original clippings (Box A28-7M)
    - Barrett, Clifton Waller - 90th birthday (Box A28-7M)
    - Barrett Collections - outdated procedures (Box A28-7M)
    - Barrett Library materials - processing (Box A28-7M)
    - Barrett Library - catalogue (Box A28-7M)
    - Barrett Library - prints (Box A28-7M)
    - Barrett volunteers (Box A28-7M)
    - Barringer, Anna (Box A28-7M)
    - Barringer Family (Box A28-7M)
    - Barron Papers (Box A28-7M)
    - Barrow, William J. 1959-1963 (Box A28-7M)
    - Barrow, William J. 1954-1959 (Box A28-7N)
    - Barrow 1937-1939, 1951 (Box A28-7N)
    - Bartenstein, Fred (Box A28-7N)
    - Barter Theatre (Box A28-7N)
    - Bartlett, Eliot Fitch (Box A28-7N)
    - Bartlett, Paul (Box A28-7O)
    - Bartlett, William (Box A28-7O)
    - Barton, Lewis N. (Box A28-7O)
    - Barton, Samuel M. (Box A28-7O)
    - Bartram Papers (Box A28-7O)
    - Baskerville, Horace (Box A28-7O)
    - Baskerville, Mrs. Wm. R. (Box A28-7O)
    - Bass, Henry B. (see also Whitman, Walt) (Box A28-7O)
    - Bath County Virginia (Box A28-7O)
    - Battle, John S. (Box A28-7O)
    - Baugh, Miss Ethel (Box A28-7O)
    - Baugh Papers (Box A28-7O)
    - Baylor Family (Box A28-7O)
    - Baylor, Richard (Box A28-7O)
    - Baylor mss (Box A28-7O)
    - BC Research (Box A28-7O)
    - Beale, John (Box A28-7O)
    - Beale, Lucy Brown (Box A28-7O)
    - Beale, Thomas Jefferson (Box A28-7O)
    - Beams, Jesse W. (Box A28-7O)
    - Bean, William B. (Box A28-7O)
    - Bean, William (Box A28-7P)
    - Bean, William - publication of Walter Reed... (Box A28-7P)
    - Bear, James (Box A28-7P)
    - Beard, Charles (Box A28-7P)
    - Beattie, Ann 1985-1989 (Box A28-7P)
    - Beauregard, P.G.T. (Box A28-7P)
    - Beckford, William-Vathek (Box A28-7P)
    - Beckley, John (Box A28-7P)
    - Bedford, Duke of (Box A28-7P)
    - Beer, Thomas (Box A28-7P)
    - Beerbohm, Max (Box A28-7P)
    - Beirne (Box A28-7P)
    - Belitt, Ben (Box A28-7P)
    - Bell, Whitfield J. (Box A28-7P)
    - Bell, Whitfield, Jr. (Box A28-7P)
    - Bell & Howell (Box A28-7P)
    - Belle Grove, Frederick Co. Virginia (Box A28-7P)
    - Bello, Andres (Box A28-7Q)
    - Bemiss, FitzGerald (Box A28-7Q)
    - Bemiss, Samuel M. 1947-1963 (Box A28-7Q)
    - Benjamin, Judah P. (Box A28-7Q)
    - Benjamin, Mary A. (Box A28-7Q)
    - Benjamin, Park (Box A28-7Q)
    - Benton, Thomas Hart (Box A28-7Q)
    - Beres, Pierre (Box A28-7Q)
    - Berkeley, Dr. A.R. (Box A28-7Q)
    - Berkeley, Francis L. (Box A28-7Q)
    - Berkeley, Norborne (Box A28-7Q)
    - Berkeley, Sir William (Box A28-7Q)
    - Berkeley Family (Box A28-7Q)
    - Berkeley manuscripts (Box A28-7R)
    - Berkeley - Barn Elms mss (Box A28-7R)
    - Berkeley family (Box A28-7R)
    - Berlinsky (Box A28-7R)
    - Berthier Papers (Box A28-7R)
    - Betts, Edwin M. (Box A28-7R)
    - Beverly Family (Box A28-7R)
    - Bewick (Box A28-7R)
    - Bible - mss (Box A28-7R)
    - Bible Records 1973-1989 (Box A28-7S)
    - Bibliography - 20th Century (Box A28-7S)
    - Bibliographical Society of America / Grolier Club (Box A28-7S)
    - Bicentennial Exhibit (Box A28-7S)
    - Bierce, Ambrose (Box A28-7S)
    - Binding (see also Holmes, Thomas J.) (Box A28-7S)
    - Bierce, Ambrose (Box A28-7T)
    - Blackmore, Richard Doddridge (Box A28-7T)
    - Boone, Daniel, Portraits (Box A27-7T)
    - Bowers, Fredson (Box A28-7T)
    - Boyeson, H.H. (Box A28-7T)
    - Bowie, James (Box A28-7T)
    - Bowker, R.R., Co. (Box A28-7T)
    - Boxley, Bruce (Box A28-7T)
    - Boyd, Alexander Spotswood (Box A28-7T)
    - Boyd, Belle (Box A28-7T)
    - Boyd, James (Box A28-7T)
    - Boyd, Julian (Box A28-7T)
    - Boyd, T. Munford (Box A28-7T)
    - Boyden, James Woodbury (Box A28-7T)
    - Boye (see also Maps - Virginia) (Box A28-7T)
    - Boyle, Sarah Patton (Box A28-7T)
    - Bradbury, Maj. Eugene (Box A28-7T)
    - Braddock, Gen. Edward (Box A28-7T)
    - Binding Orders Completed (Box A28-8A)
    - Bird, Sen. D.W. (Box A28-8A)
    - Bird, Sen. Lloyd C. (Box A28-8A)
    - Bishop Sale (Box A28-8A)
    - Black, Barron F. (Box A28-8A)
    - Black, Robert K. (Box A28-8A)
    - Black Studies (Box A28-8A)
    - Blackford Family (Box A28-8A)
    - Blackford, James B. 1956-1964, 1966-1968 (Box A28-8A)
    - Blackford, L. Minor (Box A28-8B)
    - Blackford, R. Colston (Box A28-8B)
    - Blackford, Randolph (Box A28-8B)
    - Blackford, Staige D., Jr. (Box A28-8B)
    - Blackford Papers (see also Jones Memorial Library) (Box A28-8B)
    - Blackman Imprints (Box A28-8B)
    - Blackmore Collection [see also Hench] (Box A28-8B)
    - Blackmore, Richard Doddridge (Box A28-8B)
    - Blackwell, Miss Addie & family (Box A28-8B)
    - Blackwell family (Box A28-8B)
    - Blaetterman (Box A28-8B)
    - Blaettermann, Prof. George (Box A28-8B)
    - Blake, Francis S. (Box A28-8B)
    - Blake, William (Box A28-8B)
    - Blakemore, John A. (Box A28-8B)
    - Blanck, Jacob (Box A28-8B)
    - Bland-Ruffin Papers (Box A28-8B)
    - Blanton, Wyndham (Box A28-8B)
    - Bledsoe, A.T. (Box A28-8B)
    - Blincoe, Dr. J. William (Box A28-8B)
    - Blotner, Joseph (Box A28-8B)
    - Blue Cross (Box A28-8B)
    - Blunt, Ruth H. (Box A28-8B)
    - Board of Trade (Box A28-8B)
    - Boatwright, J.O. (Box A28-8B)
    - Bodleian (Box A28-8B)
    - Bodoni (Box A28-8B)
    - Boeck, Leopold (Box A28-8B)
    - Bogle Family (Box A28-8B)
    - Boldridge Family (Box A28-8B)
    - Bolivar, Simon (Box A28-8C)
    - Bolling Family (Box A28-8C)
    - Bonnycastle, Prof. Charles (Box A28-8C)
    - Book Auctions (Box A28-8C)
    - Bookbinding (Box A28-8C)
    - Book Dealers (Box A28-8C)
    - Bookline Alert - Missing Books and Manuscripts (BAMBAM) (Box A28-8C)
    - Bookplates - correspondence & copies (Box A28-8C)
    - Boothe, Armistead (Box A28-8C)
    - Borges, Jorge Luis (1988- ) (Box A28-8C)
    - Boston Atheneum (Box A28-8C)
    - Botetourt (Box A28-8C)
    - Bouldin Family (Box A28-8C)
    - Bowden, William L. (Box A28-8C)
    - Bowers, Fredson L. (Box A28-8C)
    - Bowers, F.T. 1947-1951 (Box A28-8C)
    - Bowers, Mrs. Fredson (Box A28-8C)
    - Bowles, Paul (Box A28-8C)
    - Bradley, Dr. Samuel B. (Box A28-8D)
    - Brady, James D. (Box A28-8D)
    - Braithwaite, William Stanley (Box A28-8D)
    - Branch Papers (Box A28-8D)
    - Brandeis, Louis D. (Box A28-8D)
    - Braxton, Allen Caperton (Box A28-8D)
    - Braxton, Carter (Box A28-8D)
    - Breckenridge Family (Box A28-8D)
    - Breckinridge-Preston (Box A28-8D)
    - Breckinridge, James (Box A28-8D)
    - Breeden, Sen. Edward L. (Box A28-8D)
    - Bremo (Box A28-8D)
    - Bridgewater College (Box A28-8D)
    - Bristol, UK (Box A28-8D)
    - Bristol, Roger 1951-1953 (Box A28-8D)
    - British Envoys to America, 1791-1891 (Box A28-8D)
    - British Manuscripts relative to Virginia 1953-1959 (Box A28-8D)
    - British memos (?) re: Virginia records (Box A28-8E)
    - British Museum (Box A28-8E)
    - British Museum - accession sheets (Box A28-8E)
    - British researchers (Box A28-8E)
    - Broadus, John (Box A28-8E)
    - Brock Collection (Box A28-8E)
    - Brock Papers 1987-1990 (Box A28-8E)
    - Brockenbrough, John White (see also Johnston, Robert et al) (Box A28-8E)
    - Brodnax Papers (Box A28-8E)
    - Bromson, M.A. 1951 (Box A28-8E)
    - Bromson, Maury A. (Box A28-8E)
    - Brooks, James (Box A28-8E)
    - Brooks, Mrs. Nelson M. (Box A28-8E)
    - Brooks, Philip C. (Box A28-8E)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck (Box A28-8E)
    - Broun, Philip H. (Box A28-8E)
    - Brown, Alex (Box A28-8E)
    - Brown, Charles Brockden (Box A28-8E)
    - Brown, David Tucker (Box A28-8E)
    - Brown, Henry James (Box A28-8E)
    - Brown, John Carter, Library (Box A28-8E)
    - Brown, Ralph M. (Box A28-8E)
    - Brown, Robert B. (Box A28-8E)
    - Brown, Stuart E. (Box A28-8E)
    - Brown University (Box A28-8E)
    - Browne, Sir Thomas (Box A28-8E)
    - Brownell, William C. (Box A28-8E)
    - Browning, Robert (Box A28-8E)
    - Brownlow, Louis (Box A28-8E)
    - Bruccoli, M.J. (Box A28-8E)
    - Bruce, David (Box A28-8E)
    - Bruce, Elizabeth (Box A28-8F)
    - Bruce Family (Box A28-8F)
    - Bruce, Dr. Philip Alexander (Box A28-8F)
    - Bruce, Walter Coles (Box A28-8F)
    - Bruce-Shepperson (Box A28-8F)
    - Bryan, Daniel (Box A28-8F)
    - Bryan, David Tennant (Box A28-8F)
    - Bryan, Stewart (Box A28-8F)
    - Bryant, Vaughn (Box A28-8F)
    - Bryant, William Cullen (Box A28-8F)
    - Brydon, Rev. G. MacLaren (Box A28-8F)
    - Bruccoli-Clark Research (Box A28-8F)
    - Bruccoli, Matthew J. (Box A28-8F)
    - Bruccoli-Clark-Layman Inc. (Box A28-8F)
    - Buck Family (Box A28-8F)
    - Buckingham County (Box A28-8F)
    - Buckley Amendment (Box A28-8F)
    - Budget - Book Funds 1988-1989 (Box A28-8G)
    - Budget - Equipment 1988-1989 (Box A28-8G)
    - Budget - General 1988-1989 (Box A28-8G)
    - Budget - FY - Personal Services 1988-1989 (Box A28-8G)
    - Budget - Student 1988-1989 (Box A28-8G)
    - Budget - Travel 1988-1989 (Box A28-8G)
    - Budgets - Expenditure 1970-1982 (Box A28-8G)
    - Budget (old) pre-1970 (Box A28-8G)
    - Budget - MSS Dept / Special Collections Dept 1987-1988 (Box A28-8H)
    - Budgets 1982-1987 (Box A28-8H)
    - Budget - Binding & Appraisals 1988-1990 (Box A28-8I)
    - Budget - Book Funds 1989-1990 (Box A28-8I)
    - Book Fund Reports 1989-1990 (Box A28-8I)
    - Budget - Equipment 1989-1990 (Box A28-8I)
    - Budget - General 1989-1990 (Box A28-8I)
    - Budget - Travel 1989-1990 (Box A28-8I)
    - Budgets - Student Expenditure Payroll 1979-1984 (Box A28-8J)
    - Buford Family Papers (Box A28-8J)
    - Buford Papers (1984- ) (Box A28-8J)
    - Buhler, Curt F. 1950-1951 (Box A28-8J)
    - Bullock, Helen Duprey (Box A28-8J)
    - Bulwer, Sir Henry (Box A28-8J)
    - Burke, Gordon Trist (Box A28-8J)
    - Burke, Mrs. Gordon Trist (Box A28-8J)
    - Burns, Robert (Box A28-8J)
    - Burns, Vincent Godfrey (Box A28-8J)
    - Burr, Aaron (Box A28-8J)
    - Burruss Family Papers (Box A28-8K)
    - Burton, Patricia (Box A28-8K)
    - Burwell Family (Box A28-8K)
    - Burwell, Letitia M. (Box A28-8K)
    - Butt, Marshall W. (Box A28-8K)
    - Butterfield, Lyman H. 1948-1963 (Box A28-8K)
    - Button Family (Box A28-8K)
    - Byars, Charles W. (Box A28-8K)
    - Bynner, Witter (Box A28-8K)
    - Byrd, Gary (Box A28-8L)
    - Byrd - General (Box A28-8L)
    - Byrd, Harry Flood, Sr. 1965-1988 (Box A28-8L)
    - Byrd, Harry Flood, Jr. (Box A28-8L)
    - Byrd, Harry F. - Robertson matters 1986-1987 (Box A28-8L)
    - Byrd, Richard E. (Box A28-8L)
    - Byrd, Ruth Evelyn 1940-1951 (Box A28-8L)
    - Byrd, William (Box A28-8L)
    - Byrd, William, II (Box A28-8L)
    - Byron (Box A28-8L)
    - C misc. 1929-1953 (Box A28-8M)
    - C misc. 1954-1973 (Box A28-8N)
    - C misc. 1974-1984 (Box A28-8O)
    - C misc. 1985-1989 (Box A28-8P)
    - Cabell Foundation (Box A28-8Q)
    - Cabell-Gwathmey Collection (Box A28-8Q)
    - Cabell, Hartwell (Box A28-8Q)
    - Cabell, James Branch (Box A28-8Q)
    - Cabell, Mrs. James Branch (Box A28-8Q)
    - Cabell Family 1989 (Box A28-8R)
    - Cabell, James L. (Box A28-8R)
    - Cabell, Joseph C. - deposit receipts, etc. (Box A28-8R)
    - Cabell, Nicholas (Box A28-8R)
    - Cabell Papers (Box A28-8R)
    - Cabell, William H. (Box A28-8R)
    - Cabell, William H. - diaries (Box A28-8R)
    - Cable, George Washington (Box A28-8R)
    - Cady, Danine Lyaston (Box A28-8R)
    - Calcott, Emily S. (Box A28-8R)
    - Caldwell, Erskine (Box A28-8R)
    - Calhoun, John C. (Box A28-8R)
    - Cambridge Bibliographical Society (Box A28-8R)
    - Cambridge Imprints (Box A28-8R)
    - Cameron, William E. (Box A28-8R)
    - Campbell, Charles - Collection (Box A28-8R)
    - Campbell, Edmund S. (Box A28-8R)
    - Campbell, John (Box A28-8R)
    - Campbell, Philip Barraud (Box A28-8R)
    - Campbell, Robert (Box A28-8R)
    - Campbell, T. Bowyer (Box A28-8R)
    - Campbell, Mrs. Thomas (Box A28-8S)
    - Campbell Family (Box A28-8S)
    - Canaday, John (Box A28-8S)
    - Cannon, James (Box A28-8S)
    - Carbide & Carbon Chemicals Corp. (Box A28-8S)
    - Cards (Box A28-8S)
    - Cardwell, Gary L. (Box A28-8S)
    - Cardwell, Richard H. (Box A28-8S)
    - Carleton, Gen. (Box A28-8S)
    - Carnegie Study of United States Art (Box A28-8S)
    - Carolinas - Colonies (Box A28-8S)
    - Carpenter, Margaret, Estate of 1985-1988 (Box A28-8S)
    - Carr Papers (Box A28-8S)
    - Carr and Cary Papers (Box A28-8S)
    - Carrier, Charles J. - Company (Box A28-8S)
    - Carriere, Joseph (Box A28-8S)
    - Carriers Address (Box A28-8S)
    - Carrington Family Letters (Box A28-8S)
    - Carrington, Edward (Box A28-8S)
    - Carrington, Tazewell (Box A28-8S)
    - Carroll, Charles (Box A28-8T)
    - Carroll, James (Box A28-8T)
    - Carson, Connie (Box A28-8T)
    - Carson, Jane D. (Box A28-8T)
    - Carter, Charles (Box A28-8T)
    - Carter, Henry Rose (Box A28-8T)
    - Carter, Landon (Box A28-8T)
    - Carter, Landon of Sabine Hall (Box A28-8T)
    - Carter, Robert Hill 1951-1963 (Box A28-8T)
    - Carter, Robert "King" (see also Guggenheim - FLB) 1951-1984 (Box A28-9A)
    - Carter, Robert Wormley (Box A28-9A)
    - Carter Papers (Box A28-9A)
    - Carter Papers - Microfilm (Box A28-9A)
    - Carter, Susan N. (see also Carter-Smith Papers) (Box A28-9A)
    - Carter-Smith Papers (Box A28-9A)
    - Cartoons (Box A28-9A)
    - Cartwright, John (Box A28-9A)
    - Caruthers, William A. (Box A28-9A)
    - Casteen, John (Box A28-9A)
    - Catalogue of American Portraits (Box A28-9A)
    - Cataloguing (Box A28-9A)
    - Cather, Willa (Box A28-9B)
    - Catlin, Randolph (Box A28-9B)
    - Cauthen, Irby B. (Box A28-9B)
    - Cavalier Daily (Box A28-9B)
    - Cave Family (Box A28-9B)
    - Census Microfilms (Box A28-9B)
    - Cocke Papers 1948-1979 (Box A28-9B)
    - College Bowl (Box A28-9B)
    - Conservation Center for Art & Historic Artifacts 1984-1987 (Box A28-9B)
    - Conservation 1985-1986 (Box A28-9B)
    - Copyright (Box A28-9B)
    - Cemeteries ( -1988) (Box A28-9C)
    - Center for the Coordination of Foreign Manuscript Copying (Box A28-9C)
    - Central Atlantic Environment Council (Box A28-9C)
    - Cesare, Oscar E. (Box A28-9C)
    - Chawick, Joseph (Box A28-9C)
    - Chadwyck-Healey, Inc. (1988- ) (Box A28-9C)
    - Chamberlain, Bernard P. (Box A28-9C)
    - Chamberlayne, A. Atkinson (Box A28-9C)
    - Chameleon (Box A28-9C)
    - Chandler, Desmond B. (Box A28-9C)
    - Channing, William E. (Box A28-9C)
    - Chapin Library 1938-1951 (Box A28-9C)
    - Chappell, Warren (Box A28-9C)
    - Chapter & Verse (Box A28-9C)
    - Charlotte County (see also Atkinson-Chamberlayne, Mrs. Anne) (Box A28-9C)
    - Charlottesville (Box A28-9C)
    - Charlottesville Bar (Box A28-9C)
    - Charlottesville - Bicentennial (Box A28-9C)
    - Charlottesville Seal (Box A28-9C)
    - Chase, Samuel (Box A28-9C)
    - Chaucer (Box A28-9C)
    - Checking Account (Box A28-9C)
    - Cherokee Indians (Box A28-9C)
    - Chesapeake Book Company (Box A28-9C)
    - Chesapeake & Ohio Railroad (Box A28-9C)
    - Chesterfield County Inventory (Box A28-9C)
    - Cheuse, Alan 1989 (Box A28-9C)
    - Cheves, Langdon (Box A28-9C)
    - Chicago, University of 1940-1951 (Box A28-9C)
    - Child, Lydia Maria (Box A28-9D)
    - Childs, J. Rives (Box A28-9D)
    - China (Box A28-9D)
    - China - University of Virginia holdings re: (Box A28-9D)
    - Chinard, Gilbert (Box A28-9D)
    - Chisolm, William G. (Box A28-9D)
    - Chiswick Book Shop (Box A28-9D)
    - Chitwood, Oliver P. (Box A28-9D)
    - Chopin, Kate (Box A28-9D)
    - Christ Church (Box A28-9D)
    - Christ Church - Alexandria, Virginia (Box A28-9D)
    - Christian, Margaret (Box A28-9D)
    - Christmas Cards (1966- ) (Box A28-9E)
    - Chronological Catalogue and Article re: (Box A28-9E)
    - Church, Merton Elbridge (Box A28-9E)
    - Church, Randolph (Box A28-9E)
    - Church History - Virginia (Box A28-9F)
    - Church Records (Box A28-9F)
    - Church Records - Diocese of Southern Virginia (Box A28-9F)
    - Church Records - Diocese of Southwestern Virginia (Box A28-9F)
    - Church Records - Diocese of Virginia (Box A28-9F)
    - Church Records - Episcopal (Box A28-9F)
    - Church Records - Methodist (Box A28-9F)
    - Church Records - Presbyterian (Box A28-9F)
    - Churches - Baptist (Box A28-9F)
    - Churchill, Winston (Box A28-9F)
    - City Book Auction (Box A28-9F)
    - Civil Rights Collections (Box A28-9F)
    - Civil War 1967-1985 (Box A28-9G)
    - Civil War - Letters (Box A28-9G)
    - Civil War - Navy (Box A28-9G)
    - Civil War 1986-1989 (Box A28-9H)
    - Claiborne, Herbert (Box A28-9H)
    - Claiborne Manuscripts (Box A28-9H)
    - Claiborne, Robert W. (Box A28-9H)
    - Clapp, Verner W. (Box A28-9H)
    - Clark, T.D. (Box A28-9H)
    - Clark, The Arthur H. Company (Box A28-9H)
    - Clark, Mrs. Eliot (Box A28-9H)
    - Clark, George Rogers (Box A28-9H)
    - Clark, Raymond B. (Box A28-9H)
    - Clark, William (Box A28-9I)
    - Clark, William Andrew Memorial Library (Box A28-9I)
    - Clarke County Historical Society (Box A28-9I)
    - Clay, Henry (Box A28-9I)
    - Clay, John Randolph (Box A28-9I)
    - Clayton, John B. (Box A28-9I)
    - Claytor, Gertrude B. (Box A28-9I)